KEVIN ADRIÁN RODRÍGUEZ RUIZ

Full stack developer

About me

Chemical engineer and Master in computing with five years of experience in software development.

Self-disciplined person and excited about integrating multiple disciplines and making things easier and accessible.

Knowledge of web applications, Python, Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs and Amazon Web Services.

Interests

Web applications development. Bioinformatics. Phenomena Modelling and Optimization. Learning new engineering/science topics.

Languages

Spanish (native) English (fluent) French (basic)

Contact

Bogotá, Colombia. 111156 (+57 1) 6698229 (+57) 3057052399 karodriguezr@unal.edu.co LinkedIn profile GitHub public repositories

SKILLS

Java, Javascript, Node.js, Python, Reactjs, Amazon Web Services, Spring Framework, Django Framework, Git, Postgres, MongoDB, REST, NoSQL, Scrum, Docker.

Programs: VS Code, Intellij Idea, Aspen Plus.

EXPERIENCE

Consultant (Amaris Consulting, 2019)

+ Oficina en línea. Full stack developer. Web application for the management of insurance policies. Technologies: Reactjs, Redux, Serverless, Amazon Web Services (Lambda, API Gateway, Dynamodb, Redis, CloudFormation).

Software Engineer (Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, 2018 - 2019)

+ ANSEP. Astrocyte Neuron Simulation Environment Platform. Design and development. Web platform for the analysis of genomescale metabolic reconstructions related to the study of neurodegenerative diseases. Technologies: Python, R, Django, Reactjs, Docker, Postgresql.

Systems Analyst (Software Colombia SAS, 2015 - 2018)

- + SCmail. Design, development and maintenance. Massive email marketing platform. Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Nodejs, Gradle, Amazon Web Services (EC2, Lambda, S3, Dynamodb, SES, Autoscale, CodeDeploy, SQS).
- + SCmail upClient. Development and maintenance. Desktop application for the upload of directories/files from a local drive to a repository on Amazon S3. Technologies: Java, JavaFX, AWS.
- + Elogic Monitor. Design, development and support. Desktop application for the generation of digital signatures, encryption, and files upload, it can be invoked from all web browsers. Technologies: Javascript, Java and JavaFX.

Academic projects (2017-2019)

+ Rescurves. Design and development. Open source MS Excel Add-in aimed to ease the three-dimensional plotting of residue curves maps for quaternary systems. Technologies: C#, VSTO.

+ Master's final work: CAMD. Design and development. Desktop application to solve the Computer Aided Molecular Design (CAMD) problem of finding the most suitable solvent for a liquid-liquid separation. It makes use of multi-objective optimization and databases mining algorithms. Technologies: Java, Mongodb.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2019	M. Eng. in Systems Engineering and Computing Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)
2018 - 2019	Exchange Student in the MSc in Advanced Catalysis and Molecular Modelling Universitat de Girona (Spain)
2009 - 2015	Bachelor's degree in Chemical Engineering Universidad Nacional de Colombia (Colombia)